Madeleine Kasemichael Software Engineer

(646) 418-5400 | MMKASEMICHAEL@GMAIL.COM | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

Columbia University Fullstack Bootcamp graduate proficient in Javascript, HTML, CSS and MYSQL with proven experience in developing code for both front end and back end development. With a background in theatre and early childhood education, she has gained experience with managing and leading teams, problem solving, and has a flexible approach to projects with the ability to adapt to changing circumstances.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL, NoSQL, GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL, Express, React, Node, Handlebars, jQuery, Bootstrap

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Fellow August 2023 - November 2023

Columbia Engineering Bootcamps

- Developed game web application, using a React frontend with Bcrypt authentication and Boardgame.io with a backend of Apollo, GraphQL, and Express
- Lead a team to create a full stack pet social media web application with CRUD functionality, Bcrypt authentication and a backend with Sequelize and Express
- Built a night out planner using vanilla Javascript and third-party API's for weather and maps
- Created a logo generator using Inquirer to run in the terminal and build personalized logos

Senior Center Director • 2018 - 2023 • NYC

New York Kids Club And NY Preschool

- Oversaw multiple locations partnering and mentoring management of schools. Ensuring all standards of DOH, DOE, FDNY, DOB are met and exceeded.
- Planned and implemented sales strategies, exceeding yearly sales goals by >20%, maintained and upheld students and staff compliance. Gave tours and provided information to prospective clients.
- Maintained excellent client relationships spanning several years,
- Scheduled and provided training to new hire client services team members during the onboarding process. Interviewed potential new teachers and client services team members

Production Assistant • 2017-2019 • NYC

Todo Productions

• Assisted lead Production Assistant, assisted in setup/ breakdown of events, running events, fulfilling clients' riders.

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Advanced CPR Certified, Proficient in Google Suite and Microsoft Office, Excellent organizational and time management skills, Attention to details.

EDUCATION

CERTIFICATE • FULLSTACK SOFTWARE ENGINEERING BOOTCAMP • COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY • New York, NY • 2023 B.A. THEATRE • DESALES UNIVERSITY • Center Valley, PA •, 2018